Once upon a time, the sea level continued to rise,
"Land submarine, to the South Pole"
submerging most places worldwide.
Fortunately with Kyoto being a basin, it still stands,
but if the water level continues to rise, eventually
the waters will exceed the mountains and surge in,
sinking this Rakuyou after five days.
The conference at Kyoto prefecture continued day and night,
concluding that I, Captain Higuchi and my crew, am entrusted with our fate.
Captain
We will depart to discover the reason of the founder to save Kyoto.
Engineer
I don't cook.
I am the engineer, and additionally, the harpooner.
I am the head interpreter.
Communicator
If you speak with feeling, communication with anyone is possible.
Lookout
Leave the discovering to me!
To all the ladies, I'll be leaving Japan shortly,
but I'll definitely be back, and so, "See you!"
Uh, um...
What should I be...?
Please do the laundry.
Make something to eat.
Buy me some bread.
You go...
Yes?
fire the wave motion gun.
Eh?
By the way, where are we headed?
Maybe the South Pole?
Must be that the ice melted
causing the sea level to rise.
Would it really melt so rapidly?
I want a salad.
You should be more concerned for our health.
I really don't like raw vegetables.
Senpai, please do something about it.
It's beer after work, right?!
I'll have shark fin and caviar.
It's cold.
It's an island of ice, of course it's cold.
The South Pole should continue even further.
You must always be catching colds, huh?
None of your business.
I thought I'd make it big selling machines that make icebergs but, well...
Maybe they would sell better during summer.
Won't you buy one?
Very well, I'll get one.
You, go pay for it.
Huh, Master? Er— Captain...
Good evening!
Who would you be?
I—
I was born entirely for our encounter!
Jougasaki-san, she's not whom you seek!
I'm getting off here.
This is fate.
Will you be alright?
Yeah. I'll leave the rest to you.
Got it.
Huh, Master?
Er— Captain...
Take care.
I have a bit of business to attend to,
I'll ask you to take care of the rest.
Wait...
Akashi-san?
At this rate, the elephants will drown.
I'll guide them to the Okazaki Zoo.
What about our mission?
May fate allow us to meet again.
Senpai, hang in there.
Everyone has a role in life.
You will become a hero.
Huh?
You cooked this well.
To be able able to eat shark fin, caviar, and foie gras at a place like this...
It really is delicious, this Iberian pig.
However, from here on we're nearing the final battle.
It's here.
That's what's melting the ice.
In literature, it was "red bean initiation," written "small bean initiation."
Red bean initiation
Small bean initiation
However, he's mistaken it for "Ozu initiation."
Ozu initiation
He was born in the Kansai region,
so he might be waiting for a tsukkomi.
Seriously?
At this rate we'll be crushed!
Have you forgotten?
This is normally a land submarine.
You, what is it that you desire?
Unsatisfied,
I remain unsatisfied.
That's because you actually want to eat red beans.
Is that so?
When you want a meal but munch on snacks, your stomach feels unsatisfied.
With the stomach full, being able to eat a dessert is not a surprise.
I don't really understand, but give me something.
You got it.
It's canned red beans, enjoy it.
Then you will be satisfied.
Give me more.
Take this.
Sorry. You let your guard down.
Good job.
Well, this should be fine.
We did it.
Yeah, we did it.
Wow.
A rainbow, how romantic.
Will Kyoto be saved with this?
Well, who knows?
Was this truly the cause?
Well...
With all of Earth's ice melted, it may become too hot for man and we might perish.
What will we do now?
From the start, a floating continent may not have existed.
Riding the waves smoothly, going with the current is for the better.
That story is unbelievable.
Starting with the story's structure to the scenario up,
I mean, in my opinion, this dream's logic is...