"Land Submarine of Love and Fishing"
I think Ozu is an asshole.
He farts the moment before the
matsutake rice enters my mouth,
he mixes all the wasabi in the dip and eats the soba like nothing is wrong.
You'd definitely meet him during a walk after dark.
He puts one part coffee in four parts milk,
and he grabs and buys books from the bottom of the stack.
When he walks, he totters,
and his face is generally unpleasant.
The way he skillfully drags people along is also unpleasant.
But, has that guy ever truly gone fishing before?
And so I arrived at the Kamogawa.
But Ozu hasn't shown up.
I'm going to meet up with Akashi-san. I'll be right back.
-Ozu
Where are you planning to meet her?
A harpoon?
Fishing?
Fishing as in to catch a fish with a hook through the mouth just to return it back to water?
That fishing?
It's a hook, a hook!
It sticks in the mouth.
I won't forgive not properly cooking and eating what you fish.
You would normally eat what you fish.
Akashi-san?
Ah, no, I'm dealing with Ozu now.
It seems I was being chased.
It felt like we met eye-to-eye.
Get inside.
Um...
That's the figurehead.
It's a statue.
Welcome, to the Land Submarine.
Land Submarine?
That harpoon.
That was the cause of my haze.
For extracting that for me, I am—
Captain, Akashi-san.
What?
He's planning to abduct Akashi-san. What should I do?
Who's "he"?
Why don't you get him with that harpoon, Captain?
"Him"?
Oh, I see. The only person who can save her is me!
Did you see that just now?
The captain abandoned this boat.
Do you think a man who abandons his duty can save Akashi-san?
Is that really all right?
As it stands, that captain will do as he pleases,
and only the captain can move this boat.
What will you do with this captain-less boat?
The future will change based on your decision.
Future?
For the sake of my future...
Raise the anchor! Set sail!
We're after Akashi-san's bus, get ahead of them!
You're quite the sharp one,
Captain.
"Captain"?
There's a subtle change in Akashi-san's movement.
Subtle?
Akashi-san?
Ah, Akashi-san.
Oh, I promised Ozu I'd go fishing with him...
Moth—
By the way, Captain, do you fish?
Fishing?
What, what, what, what's that noise?
It's the clay pipes.
Huh?
Who are you?
The new deputy.
What's with that attitude?
I'm the captain, I'm your superior!
Instruction manual.
*Please read before use
I couldn't help but to grab it.
Another new deputy?
I felt it was a quick change.
User manual.
The instructions for the land submarine were written inside.
How to operate
Hey! Deputy!
I'll explain.
You should've carefully read that from the beginning.
That man began talking as if
he had memorized everything.
It seems this boat can advance effortlessly in solid matter by changing its surroundings into water-like substances.
The moment we hit clay pipes,
I was dismissed from my duty as captain.
Never mind that, more importantly, Akashi-san.
He's holding the harpoon alone and heading this way.
He's going to pierce the boat with the harpoon!
The torpedoes.
The torpedoes!
I see. I had the same thought.
You're taking my idea,
but I'll turn a blind eye this time.
Go ahead and use it.
Torpedo, loaded.
I, at that moment, didn't care about Akashi-san.
I just wanted to change these poor surroundings.
That is the truth.
Captain! Please shoot!
Well then!
Oh, isn't this God's Rock?
Don't you want to become drippy like a towel?
You're... not Ozu.
Thank you. Your cleared heart discovered this God's Rock.
I returned to Kamo River with Ozu waiting.
Oh, I waited for quite a long time.
I've fished more than enough today,
so I'll be leaving now.
Also, I also invited Akashi-san, but she couldn't make it today.
Instead, she said she wanted to give you this memo.
I'm writing a report today,
so I can't participate in fishing.
Fish you could catch that I'd be glad to receive:
Octopus and tuna?
Just where did Ozu say we were going to fish?
And for that matter, what did he catch today?
This may be a place to philosophize.
What's with that story?
It wasn't the least bit interesting.
Probably a more or less true story that did not involve us.
I'm done talking!